# Anshul Bhardwaj

I'm a software engineer with 3+ years of experience in backend and distributed systems. Currently, I work at Salesforce. Before that, I worked at Flipkart and Oyo. I'm passionate about designing efficient algorithms, optimizing code for performance, and ensuring system reliability.



CGPA: 8.79/10

$\searrow$	anshulbh9@gmail.con	n
/°\	anshalon y w gindincon	

anshulbh.netlify.app/

github.com/anshulbh9

### +91 8572041500

linkedin.com/in/anshulbh9

medium.com/@anshulbh9

# **EDUCATION**

## **B.E. Computer Engineering**

Thapar Institute of Engineering and Technology, Patiala, Punjab &

07/2016 - 07/2020

### Courses

- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Machine learning

- Operating Systems
- Data Analytics and Visualization
- Computer Networks
- Software Engineering

# WORK EXPERIENCE

### Member of technical staff

Bengaluru, Karnataka Data Cloud (AKA Customer Data Platform, CDP and Genie) is the single source of truth (SSOT) and the foundational data layer for all data for AI in the Salesforce ecosystem, where all the data from various sources are managed for an enterprise.

### Achievements/Tasks

- Working in the control plane team, creating a platform for onboarding new tenants and scaling the platform to multiple geographies.
- Created a generic framework for different types of ingress and egress connectors such as AWS, Azure, Snowflake, and GCP.
- Upgraded Postgres to 14.0 version with logical replication without any downtime. Worked on terraform script to define resource policies.

## **Software Engineer**

## Flipkart 🗷

03/2021 - 10/2022 Flipkart is the largest ecommerce website in india. Bengaluru, Karnataka

### Achievements/Tasks

- Worked as part of the Promise Engine team in the supply chain division, which is responsible for computing end-to-end physical delivery capabilities of products to customers.
- Built a predictive intervention in capacity allocation through systematic automation service and designed a source capacity model for the warehouse, improved the SLA for specific listings, improved the overall user experience, and maintained the same SLA period during sale
- Dockerizing and onboarding micro-services to k8s, creating CI/CD pipelines and setting up cosmos for monitoring and adding alerts for application health and latencies.
- Active part of on-call rotation to handle production issues and created action items to improve overall reliability and availability.

# **Sofware Engineer**

Oyo Rooms 🗷

08/2020 - 03/2021 OYO Rooms is an Indian multinational hospitality chain of leased and franchised hotels, homes, and living space. Gurugram, HR

- Integrated and onboarded oyo hotels to other sites like Trivago, Skyscanner, and Tripadvisor and integrated conversion API.
- Built a CRM scheduler service to send triggers to moengage and In house communication service.
- Following Agile methodology, creating JIRA stories and breaking down tasks and following CI/CD through Jenkins, and deploying on Kubernetes.
- Part of Campus recruitment team.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Software Engineer Intern Oyo Rooms ☑

01/2020 - 07/2020

Achievements/Tasks

Gurugram, HR

- Built Book on Google microservice where users can directly book a hotel through Google without being redirected to the Oyo website.
   Integrated with inventory, real-time pricing, ordering, and payment gateway in the microservices. Also, build a dashboard to monitor the bookings.
- Google Hotel Ads, Syncing live hotel prices to Google and Bing ads through Kafka triggers of inventory and pricing. And integrated hints and
  messaging APIs to sync the prices.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages Java, C++, Python, JavaScript. Lua, Bash

Frameworks/ Databases SpringBoot, Spring, React, Postgres, MongoDb, Aerospike, Redis, Apache Kafka, HBase

DevOps/Cloud Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, gRPC, REST, AWS, GCP

# **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

AutoComplete and Auto-Suggest| Data Structure and algorithms

Implemented the auto-suggest feature using a trie data structure, which gives a completion option based on user input.

Movie Recommendation System using twitter sentiment analysis

Movie Recommendation System that incorporates sentiment analysis from user reviews to enhance the accuracy and relevance of movie recommendations. It considers the sentiment of user reviews, offering a more personalised and insightful recommendation experience.

Library Management System

Making ER diagrams, database normalization to 3-nf and SQL queries for CRUD operations and making a spring boot application for REST API to perform CRUD operations.

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Awarded Value Champion Award 2021 [Flipkart]

HackerRank Contest Rating: 1810 and Gold Badge in HackerRank Algorithm, C++ and Python domain. ☑

Winner of Coder of the year 2018, third in switch coding MSC, Thapar ♂

T.I.E.T merit scholarship Rs.80,000.

# **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

# Data Structures and JavaScript Lead Instructor crio.do ☑

11/2021 - 02/2022

Tasks/Achievements

 As the lead mentor for multiple cohorts in Data Structures and JavaScript batches, I taught lectures and curated the curriculum.

# Software Development Bootcamp Instructor Massai School ♂

02/2022 - 04/2022

Tasks/Achievements

 Trained 50 individuals with no prior programming experience in JavaScript and React through 10 sessions, each lasting 2 hours.

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

# Open Source Contribution OpenMRS ♂

Tasks/Achievements

 Contributed to upgrading the project's Java version upgrade and maven library upgrade to ensure compatibility with the latest release.

### **Mock Interviews**

Masai School 🗷

Tasks/Achievements

 To help students become comfortable with the interview structure, I conducted mock interviews for the machine coding and data structure round of the batch.